<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Et al. Lab</title>
    <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Et al. Lab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Environmental turbulence and analysis littera Laboratory</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/images/icon_hu2547a779dfd9218acbedb132edfe59d8_88726_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Et al. Lab</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Seminar at John Hopkins Center for Environmental and Applied Fluid Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/post/invited-talk-ceafm-2020spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/post/invited-talk-ceafm-2020spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tune in to the virtual seminar 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://wse.zoom.us/j/93762992307&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://wse.zoom.us/j/93762992307&lt;/a&gt; this Friday (Feb. 26, 2021) 3 pm EST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title: “Pseudo-Volumetric Reconstruction of Velocity and Density Fields from 2D Data &amp;amp; Energy Cascade in Multiphase Flows”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Fluid turbulence is an unsteady, three-dimensional (3D) phenomenon that affects the dispersion of heat and mass in the environment and the friction (drag) at solid boundaries. To fully characterize a turbulent flow thus requires the simultaneous measurements of the fluid velocity, density, and tracer mass distributions within a fluid volume at a sufficient spatial-temporal resolution. This is a non-trivial task for experimentalists because of the capital involved; it is estimated that between 8 to 12 high-speed cameras are required to do a full tomographic reconstruction of the velocity and scalar fields. Even when a high number of cameras is available, the physical constraints of a setup may preclude the deployment of such imaging system. To circumvent this technological barrier, I will present in the first part of this seminar a three-camera reconstruction method to obtain time-resolved, 3D fluid velocity and
density data from planar data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part, I will change gear to discuss the similarities and differences on the interscale energy transfer in particle-laden and bubble-laden plumes. Examples of such plumes are found in subsea oil spills, in chemical mixing tanks, and in volcanic eruptions. Currently, our ability to predict their hydrodynamic behaviors is limited by our knowledge of the turbulence that exists in them. I will present combined experimental and numerical results to bridge this gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Announcement link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.jh.edu/ceafm/weekly-seminar/Spring21/Lai.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://pages.jh.edu/ceafm/weekly-seminar/Spring21/Lai.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk for this fall&#39;s Cornell Fluids Seminar</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/post/invited-talk-cfs-2020fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 17:18:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/post/invited-talk-cfs-2020fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I have presented the research from my on-going collaboration with colleagues in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lanl.gov/projects/shocktube/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Extreme Fluids Team&lt;/a&gt; at Los Alamos National Lab. The abstract for this talk is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Tuesday, November 17, 2020, 12 pm EST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title: Removing roadblocks in variable-density turbulence research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Turbulent mixing involving two fluids of drastically different densities (density ratio $\rho_{2}/\rho_{1} \gg 1$) differs from that found in constant-density or Boussinesq fluids. The non-negligible inertial differences between fluid parcels create the so-called &lt;em&gt;mixing asymmetry&lt;/em&gt;; the hydrodynamics of a light fluid penetrating into a dense fluid is different from that of the dense fluid into the lighter one. Existing turbulence theories and models based on constant-density flows are inadequate when they are used to predict variable-density (VD) flows. Further, it becomes necessary to simultaneously measure density and velocity as the density is now an active scalar. The correlation between density fields and vortical structures is crucial in understanding the effects of fluid inertia on flow hydrodynamics. In this talk, we present an analytical and an experimental tool to study VD turbulence – (1) the generalization of the von Karman-Howarth-Monin (KHM) equation to include VD effects and (2) a three-camera reconstruction method to obtain time-resolved, 3D fluid velocity and density data from planar data. To illustrate the methods, we have applied them to analyze experimental datasets of a SF6 turbulent jet discharged into a coflowing air stream inside a wind tunnel; $\rho_{2}/\rho_{1} \approx 4$ at the jet nozzle exit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awarded Small Bets Seed Grant 2020!</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/post/small-bets-award-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 17:18:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/post/small-bets-award-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like a knife through butter- glacial melt by ocean plumes investigated in novel laboratory experiments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; has been awarded the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://research.gatech.edu/gt-community/funding-opportunities/gt-annual-seed-grant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Small Bets Seed Grant 2020&lt;/a&gt;. This is a collaboration with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eas.gatech.edu/people/robel-dr-alexander&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Alexander Robel&lt;/a&gt; from the School of Earth and Atmospheric Sciences at Georgia Tech. We are excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a synopsis-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melt from the Greenland and Antarctic ice sheets are increasingly contributing to ongoing global sea level rise. This ice sheet mass loss is primarily driven by the thinning, retreat and acceleration of glaciers in contact with the ocean. Observations from the field and remote-sensing platforms indicates that glaciers are sensitive to changes at the ice-ocean interface and that the increase in submarine melting is likely to be driven by the discharge of meltwater from underneath the glacier (known as subglacial meltwater plumes). The melting of glacier ice also directly inputs a large volume of freshwater into the ocean, potentially causing significant changes in the circulation of ocean waters which regulate the transport of heat on Earth, making ice-ocean interactions an important potential amplifier in climate change and variability. Our ability to predict, and hence adequately response to, climate change and sea level rise therefore depends on our knowledge of the small-scale processes occurring in the vicinity of subglacial meltwater plumes at the ice-ocean interface. Currently, our understanding of the underlying physics is incomplete; for example, different parameterizations of the glacial-ocean interaction could yield melting rates that vary over a factor of five for the same heat supply from the ocean. It is then very difficult to ascertain and judge the reliability of predictive models. We propose to use laboratory experiments to study how the melt rates of glaciers in the vicinity of plumes are affected by the ice roughness, ice geometry, and ocean turbulence at the ice-ocean interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbulence statistics in a negatively buoyant multiphase plume</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/negatively-buoyant-multiphase-plume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/negatively-buoyant-multiphase-plume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multibody turbulent flow</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/project/multi-body-turbulent-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/project/multi-body-turbulent-flow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production of turbulence in an array of spheres with relative motions: air-water flows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental flows involving air or water interacting with heterogeneous objects such as particles, droplets or buildings are of great concern to the civil engineering discipline because of the modifications brought by the objects to the flow field, and hence, to the turbulent dispersion of solute and heat. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The goal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is to use high-resolution, volumetric velocity and scalar concentration field data to inform turbulence modeling of such flows. A refractive-index matched (RIM) tilting water flume will be constructed to carry out the experimental investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;











  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;bubbly-turbulent-flows.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
$\bigtriangleup $ Liquid turbulence in bubbly turbulent flows&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stratified turbulence</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/project/mixing-and-scale-interactions-in-stratified-turbulence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/project/mixing-and-scale-interactions-in-stratified-turbulence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mixing and scale interactions in stratified turbulence: improving turbulence models and estimates of oceanic mixing efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stable density stratification inhibits fluid motions in the direction of the gradients. This creates flow anisotropy and favors motions along lines of constant density (isopycnals); the everyday smoke plume horizontally intruding into its surroundings is one example. Because of anisotropy, the pathways by which kinetic energy of the fluid motions is cascaded are also anisotropic and different than that predicted by classic turbulence theories. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The goal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of this project is to use high-resolution, volumetric velocity and density experimental data to improve the predictions of turbulent flows in the presence of stratification. Experiments will focus on canonical shear flows (jets, wakes, and mixing layers) and on two-layer stratified systems subject to homogeneous isotropic turbulence (HIT) under different Brunt-Vaisala frequencies ($N^2$). Obtained data will be used to test existing RANS and LES turbulence closure models and to propose new model formulations. The experiments will be done using refractive-index matching (RIM) techniques. Attention will also be paid to match the kinematic viscosities of the RIM fluid pair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turbulent flow in porous media</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/project/turbulent-flow-in-porous-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/project/turbulent-flow-in-porous-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turbulent-laminar flow transitions in porous media: solute transport in river and groundwater&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural rivers and unpaved water channels involve turbulent surface flows over a permeable bed. Surface water enters the soil layer via infiltration and eventually becomes part of the groundwater flow. Apart from soil properties, the infiltration rate is highly dependent on the structures of the turbulent boundary layer adjacent to the porous bed. For sand beds with pore sizes of about 1mm, recent numerical studies found that the flow inside the pore matrix can become transitional and departs from the laminar Darcy flow regime; the Darcy coefficient is a function of the pore flow’s Reynolds number. Dispersion characteristics also change due to the change in flow regime. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The project goal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is to understand the different flow regimes and physics as a function of pore size and pore matrix using laboratory experiments. First part of the experimental program will focus on the effects of zero-mean flow, homogeneous isotropic turbulence (HIT) created above the porous bed. Second part will study the effects of a turbulent channel flow. Refractive-index matching (RIM) techniques will be used to measure flows inside the pores and a random-jet stirred tank will be built to create HIT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean velocity, spreading and entrainment characteristics of weak bubble plumes in unstratified and stationary water</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/weak-bubble-plumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/weak-bubble-plumes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The turbulent kinetic energy budget in a bubble plume</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/turbulent-kinetic-energy-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/turbulent-kinetic-energy-budget/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budgets of turbulent kinetic energy, Reynolds stresses, and dissipation in a turbulent round jet discharged into a stagnant ambient</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/budgets-of-turbulent-kinetic-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/budgets-of-turbulent-kinetic-energy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy cascade in a homogeneous swarm of bubbles rising in a vertical channel</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/homogeneous-swarm-of-bubbles-rising/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/homogeneous-swarm-of-bubbles-rising/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavior and dynamics of bubble breakup in gas pipeline leaks and accidental subsea oil well blowouts</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/bubble-breakup-in-gas-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/bubble-breakup-in-gas-pipeline/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Kármán–Howarth–Monin equation for variable-density turbulence</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/karmanhowarthmonin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/karmanhowarthmonin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of linear autoregressive models for estimation of energy spectra in gappy turbulent velocity data</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/linear-autoregressive-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/linear-autoregressive-models/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of Bubble Plumes in Unstratified Stagnant Water</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/an-analysis-of-bubble-plumes-in-unstratified-stagnant-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/an-analysis-of-bubble-plumes-in-unstratified-stagnant-water/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A LES-based Eulerian–Lagrangian approach to predict the dynamics of bubble plumes</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/les-based/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/les-based/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing in the Intermediate Field of Dense Jets in Cross Currents</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/mixing-in-the-intermediate-field-of-dense-jets-in-cross-currents/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/mixing-in-the-intermediate-field-of-dense-jets-in-cross-currents/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial mixing of inclined dense jet in perpendicular crossflow</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/initial-mixing-of-inclined-dense-jet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/initial-mixing-of-inclined-dense-jet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing of inclined dense jets in stationary ambient</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/mixing-of-inclined-dense-jets-in-stationary-ambient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/mixing-of-inclined-dense-jets-in-stationary-ambient/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Near-field Jet Behavior of 60° Dense Jets Discharged Into A Perpendicular Crossflow</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/near-field-jet-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/near-field-jet-behavior/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing of Inclined Dense Jets</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/mixing-of-inclined-dense-jets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/mixing-of-inclined-dense-jets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Simulation of Dominant Eddies of A Co-Flowing Jet</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/digital-simulation-of-dominant-eddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/digital-simulation-of-dominant-eddies/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JETLAG2008 - An Update</title>
      <link>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/jetlag2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Lai-etal-lab.github.io/publication/jetlag2008/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
